The AI boom is wreaking havoc on San
Francisco's real estate market, and it
will only get worse. Home prices are up
a whopping 15% from a year ago, [music]
far more than in any other major city.
Some homes are selling for millions of
dollars above their asking prices. Even
once overlooked neighborhoods like the
Outer Sunset and Outer Parkside are now
seeing some truly unhinged pricing
contests. If you want to get a sense of
the housing market whiplash, take a look
at this six-bedroom luxury home in the
city's famed [music] Russian Hill
neighborhood. It sold for $20 million in
2020, dropped to $10 million in late
2023, [music]
and then sold again this year for $24
million. The last time San Francisco
real estate drew national headlines,
home prices were sinking as white-collar
workers fled to home offices and cheaper
cities like Austin [music] or Denver.
Now San Francisco's doom loop has turned
into a boom loop, and the metro is once
again the most expensive [music] housing
market in the country, and AI is at the
center of it. The city is now at the
heart of the AI revolution, home to
household names like OpenAI and
Anthropic. [music] These companies are
luring workers with multi-million-dollar
bonuses, big equity packages, and lavish
[music] salaries. And with huge IPOs
looming, including OpenAI, SpaceX, and
Anthropic, [music]
overnight millionaires and billionaires
will almost certainly deliver more
shocks in the coming months. The city by
the bay has seen many booms and busts,
but seasoned San Franciscans tell me
this time feels different. For one, the
gold rush is really concentrated in San
Francisco proper, where well-paid
workers are all jostling for
single-family homes close to the office
and perfect for growing [music]
families. The luxury market in the $3
million and up range is super hot, but
more affordable segments and cheaper
areas nearby like Oakland haven't seen
[music] the same price gains. San
Francisco may seem like an anomaly, but
it can actually tell us a lot about the
forces shaping our national housing
market, including the K-shaped economy,
[music] the return-to-office push, and
the winners and losers of the AI age. To
learn more, head to Business Insider.
[music]